{
    "id": "1824608b3fc04fcb97595ea36d9e5886",
    "title": "Approve, Object, Oppose | Vocabulary Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "8423da40d19f4affb39d8a0a5b406a32",
            "title": "Approve, Oppose, Object | Vocabulary Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "They ............................ to the manager's decisions.",
                    "description": "'Objected' takes the preposition 'to' before an object. 'Oppose' does not take a preposition before an object. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "objected",
                        "opposed",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The family ............................ her new fiance.",
                    "description": "Approve takes the preposition 'of' before an object. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "approves",
                        "approves of",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are ............................. the idea.",
                    "description": "Object takes the preposition 'to' before the object.",
                    "answers": [
                        "objected",
                        "objected to",
                        "opposed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "In this state, parental ........................... is necessary before a seventeen-year old can obtain a driver's license.",
                    "description": "Approval is the noun form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "approve",
                        "approval",
                        "approving"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I object ........................... this.",
                    "description": "Here the 'to' after 'object' is a preposition. When 'to' is used as a preposition, it is followed by an -ing form, not an infinitive. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "to do",
                        "doing",
                        "to doing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "Mother ........................... cigar smoking.",
                    "description": "The verb 'object' needs the preposition 'to' before an object. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "objects",
                        "objects to",
                        "object to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The boy kept the dog despite his sister's ........................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "object",
                        "objective",
                        "objection"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is rude and ...........................",
                    "description": "Objectionable means intolerable. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "objective",
                        "objectionable",
                        "object"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Several of the speakers .......................... the project.",
                    "description": "'Objected' takes the preposition 'to' before an object. 'Oppose' does not take a preposition before an object. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "opposed",
                        "objected",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Many people are ............................. to the idea.",
                    "description": "Oppose can have both passive and active uses. Object is not used like this. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "objected",
                        "opposed",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The senate ............................. the new housing bill.",
                    "description": "When approve means 'pass' it does not take a preposition before the object. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "approved",
                        "approved of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The child did something his father did not .....................",
                    "description": "'Approve of' means judge as good or think highly of.",
                    "answers": [
                        "approve",
                        "approve of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}